--==圣城家园SCG-CMCT团队荣誉出品==--
字幕调校: 虚无  影片压制: laixy  招募Q号: 76846146
【 剑 鱼 行 动 】
你知道好莱坞的问题吗？
You know the problem with Hollywood?
他们都拍烂片，难以置信
Thev make shit. Unbelievable,
超级大烂片
unremarkable shit.
我并不是唱高调的导演
I'm not some wannabe filmmaker...
成天抽大麻寻找人生意义
...searching for existentialism through a haze of bong smoke.
要挑毛病的话很容易
No, it's easy to pick apart bad acting, shortsighted directing...
演员、导演和剧本都烂透了
...and a moronic stringing together of words the studios term as prose.
我说的是缺乏真实感
No, I'm talking about the lack of realism.
真实感
Realism.
这不是当今影坛的第一考量
Not a pervasive element in modern American cinematic vision.
就拿“热天午后”来说吧
Take Dog Day Afternoon, for example.
艾尔帕西诺最好的作品
Arguably Pacino's best work.
除了“疤面煞星”和“教父”
Short of Scarface and Godfather Part I, of course.
导演薜尼卢梅的功力没话说
Masterpiece of directing, easily Lumet's best.
摄影、演员和剧本都是一流的
The cinematographv, the acting, the screenplav, all topnotch.
但是…
But...
他们没有发挥到极限
...they didn't push the enyelope.
为何不让帕西诺逍遥法外呢？
What if, in Dog Day Sonny wanted to get away with it?
真的逍遥法外
Really wanted that.
让我们设想一下，要是他立刻杀死人质呢？
Now this is the tricky part. What if he started killing hostages right away?
绝不迟疑、毫不留情
No mercv, no quarter.
不答应要求，金发美女就死定了
"Meet our demands or the pretty blond gets it in the head."
砰，脑袋开花
Bam, splat.
还是不让步？少来了
What, still no bus? Come on.
他要让多少人质血肉横飞
How many innocent victims would it take for the city...
市政府才肯让步？
...to reverse its policv on hostages?
1976年没有CNN
And this is 1976. There's no CNN.
也没有有线电视或网际网路
There's no CNBC. There's no Internet.
假如是今天，一样的情况
Fast-forward to todav. Present time, same situation.
媒体马上就把新闻炒作起来
How quickly would the media make a frenzv? In hours.
从美国到欧洲都是头条新闻
It would be the biggest story from Boston to Budapest.
十名人质丧命
Ten hostages die.
二十名、三十名
Twenty, thirty.
人质一个接一个被射杀
Relentless. Bam, bim. One after another.
全都被高画质摄影机拍下来
All on hi-def, computer-enanced.
连溅出的脑浆都看得到
You can almost taste the brain matter.
只为了要一台巴士或飞机？
All for what? A bus, a plane?
或是区区的几百万元吗？
A couple million dollars that's federally insured?
当然不会，我只是想想而已
I don't think so, but... ...just a thought.
当然了
I mean, it's not...
一般电影不是这么拍，但是…
...within the realm of conventional cinema, but...
假如是呢？
...what if?
你这部电影有一个问题
There's a problem with that movie.
是吗？
Really?
它不会卖座
It wouldn't work.
为什么？
How come?
观众喜欢快乐结局
Audiences love happv endings.
帕西诺拿了钱逃之夭夭
Pacino escapes with the money.
他男友去变性，他们白头偕老
Bovfriend gets a sex change. Live happily ever after.
不行吗？
No?
不行
No.
你歧视同性恋
Homophobia.
这是道德观念，坏人不能赢
Bad guy can't win. It's a morality tale.
不管怎样，他一定要死
One way or the other, he's gotta go down.
有时候现实比电影更夸张
Well, life is stranger than fiction sometimes.
大伙儿，我得走了
You know, guys, I gotta go.
我要走了
Gotta jet.
多谢这杯咖啡
Thanks for the coffee.
史丹利，该办正事了
Stan. Time to go to work.
你来不来？
You coming?
让开，我不想再说一遍
Move. I won't sav it again.
我瞄准他了
I have a clear shot.
狙击手，待命
Shooters, stand by.
好了，现在呢？
Okay. Now what?
别担心，很快就结束了
Don't worry, folks, it's almost over.
－她好了吗？ －好了
- Is she done? - She's done.
－带她出去 －走吧
- Move her out.
放心，你会没事，笑一下嘛
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
很快就回来
You'll be back before you know it.
给我转过来
Turn the fuck around.
救援小组，快走
Rescue team, let's go.
屋顶上有谁？
Who's on the roof?
狙击手，等待指令
All shooters, you are holding for command.
他们准备开枪
All prepare their shot.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我要搞定他
I'm handling this!
别招惹毛这家伙
Don't fuck with this guy!
你会害死人质
You'll get these people killed!
屋顶有两组狙击手
We got two teams on the roof. We got a team over there.
加派人手，以防万一
Double this team up. That's your best angle.
别说话，听我说
Don't talk. Just listen.
22名人质身上
Each of the 22 hostages is wrapped
都有20磅塑胶炸药
with 20 pounds of C-4 explosives.
还有15磅的不锈钢球
Thev're also taped with 15 pounds of stainless steel ball bearings.
他们是杀伤力最强大的活动地雷
Which makes them the world 's largest clavmore mines.
可以行动了
Thev got the green light.
他在跟我讲电话
I got this guy on the phone!
别理他，我不想跟他耗下去
I'm done plaving with this asshole!
他们就像小狗戴着电击颈圈
Around their necks are radio-frequencv electronic dog collars.
只要走出院子就会遭到电击
Dog walks out of the yard, gets the shit shocked out of him. Same here.
银行就是他们的院子，别搞鬼
This bank is their vard, so don't fuck with me.
强森，你们到车子中间
Johnson, you and your partner move up between those vehicles.
－站住 －回来
- Stand down! - Get back!
站住
Stand down!
回来
Get back!
马上站住
Officer, stand down now!
他要开枪，他要开枪
He's gonna shoot! He's gonna shoot!
该死
Shit.
去救她
Get her!
快去
Go!
不，放开人质
No! Release the hostage!
不，快放开人质
她要爆炸了，找掩护
She's gone. Take cover!
不，放开她，放开她
No, no! Let her go! Let her go!
放开人质
Release the hostage!
救救我
Help me!
放开她…
Let her go. Let her go!
天啊
Jesus.
快躲开
Shit! You guys, come on!
四天前
你打算停留多久？
How long will you be here?
一个礼拜
One week.
公干或观光？
Business or pleasure?
希望都有吧
Hopefully both.
你从事哪一行？
What type of work do you do?
我是电脑顾问
I'm a consultant.
对不起
Excuse me.
请小心点，那些器材很贵
Could you be careful with that? That's expensive equipment.
这要多久？
How long will this take?
只要几分钟
A few minutes.
请坐，我马上回来
Sit down, relax. I'll be right back.
几分钟
A few minutes, huh?
他想去哪里？
Hey, where's he going?
站住
电梯往上
It's going up. Stairs.
走楼梯
请你跟我们来
Sir, could you please...?
冷静点
Easv, easy.
华府
你最好有很重要的事
This better be important.
不重要就不会找你，参议员
Wouldrt have asked you otherwise, senator.
我们接获消息
We just received word that
艾索托沃入境时被拦下来
Axl Torvalds was intercepted  entering the U.S.
什么时候？
When was this?
两小时前
Within the last two hours.
他在洛杉矶机场的海关被捕
According to my FBI source, he was nabbed in customs at LAX.
他们知道他替我们工作？
Thev know he's working for us?
应该不知道
It 's unlikely.
那是例行检查，托沃一时紧张
It was a routine check. Torvalds freaked out. Thev got luckv.
情况不妙，FBI知道吗？
This ain't good. What do the feds know?
不知道，他故意不用英语回答
Nothing vet. He's refusing to speak English.
芬兰领事馆联络了国务院
The Finnish consulate has contacted the State Department.
计划没曝光，对吧？
So we haven't been compromised?
我不确定，我正在查
I'm not sure. I'm working on that.
快去查，小子
You better get sure
要不然有人会倒大楣
because someone's cock will end up on the block...
我保证不是我
...and it won't be mine.
我了解，参议员
I understand, senator.
那就好
There you go.
密德兰，德州
你是什么人？
Well, well, well. Who are you supposed to be?
我是金姬
I'm Ginger.
金姬？
Ginger, huh?
你的好友虞姬呢？
Where's Gilligan?
国安局把你列为最危险的骇客
For someone the NSA once listed as the most dangerous hacker in America...
长得却一点也不起眼
...you sure don't look like much.
吓一跳吗？
Surprised?
我对你的一切瞭若指掌
I know evervthing about you, Stan.
你来这里推销什么？
What are you selling again?
我的老板想见你
Mv employer wants to meet you.
可恶
Shit.
你打得不是很好
You're not too good at golf.
你影响了我的手气
You're fucking up my chi.
让我来
Let me have that.
史丹利，你家里又脏又乱
This is not a nice place you got here, Stan.
我才来五分钟就深感同情
Here 5 minutes, and I already feel sorrv for myself.
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
我一摸电脑就得回去坐牢
I toucha computer,  I go back to Leavenwon'th.
回不了家，也赚不到钱
Do not pass Go, do not collect $200.
早知道你会来，我就打扫一下
If I knew you were coming, I might have cleaned up.
我不是来跟你上床的
I'm not here to suck your dick, Stanley.
你只要去见他就有钱赚
He'll pay you just to meet you.
我得去上工了
I gotta go to work.
是啊
Right.
你得去替起重机上油
Great work greasing pump jacks.
那么…
So...
你最近见过荷莉吗？
...spoke to Holly lately?
该死
Shit!
梅莉莎，荷莉在家吗？
Melissa. Is Holly home?
史丹利
你打来干嘛？
Whv are you calling here?
我只想跟荷莉说说话
I just want to talk with Holly.
今天礼拜六，她得去练足球
It's Saturday. She's at soccer.
你跟她说话是犯法的
It's illegal for you to talk to her.
别这样，这对荷莉不好
Don't do this, Mel It's not good for Holly.
你不知道什么对我女儿才好
How would you know what's good for my daughter?
你刚坐了两年牢
You spent the last two years in prison.
梅莉莎
Mel
别叫得那么亲热，史丹利
Stop calling me that, Stanley.
我只想…我只想见我的乖女儿
Look, I just... I just want to see my baby.
她不想见你，史丹利
Well, she doesn't want to see you, Stanley.
我发誓，你敢去找她
And I swear, if you trv to contact her...
赖瑞的律师会把你关进黑狱
...I'll have you thrown in a hole so dark...
让你叫天不灵、叫地不应
...Leavenwon'th will seem like two weeks in Vegas...
我还会派两个狠角色去痛扁你一顿
...during which I will personally...pay two  skineads to make a plavground out of your ass.
你这个贱女人是狗改不了吃屎
You can take the girl out of the trailer park... ...but can't take the trailer park out of the girl
我才不吃你这一套
I will not let myself be manipulated bv you, Stanley.
赖瑞才是她老爸
Larry's her father now.
赖瑞是色情片大王
Larry's the porn king of Southern Calif...
赖瑞是电影制片
Larry is a film financier.
他拍的电影能赚钱
The films he chooses are for profit
也跟你无关
and none of your business.
去求助吧
Get help.
接受心理辅导或养只狗吧
Get into a program, get a therapist, get a dog.
你最好离我女儿远一点
But whatever you do, stav away from my child.
你女儿？她是我们的女儿
Your child? She's our child.
她才不是你的女儿
She will never be your child.
忘了荷莉吧
Forget Holly.
你还在这儿干嘛？
What are you still doing here?
我开始失去耐心了
Look, I'm beginning to lose my sense of humor.
那我就直话直说
Then I'll cut to the chase.
如果你想要女儿就听我说
If you want your daughter back, you better listen up.
除非你想一直窝在这鬼地方
Unless you want to stav here in this loser existence...
眼睁睁看你女儿变成色情女星
...while your daughter grows up to be a fluffer in her new daddv's videos.
别把你自己跟我女儿混为一谈
Please don't confuse your own childhood with my daughter's.
你要好好想一下，史丹利
And look at your situation, Stanley.
你这二十个月来，向法院争取了六次
For the past 20 months, you've been in and out of court 6 times?
每次案子都被驳回
Each time your case was thrown out.
你的情况很不妙，亲爱的
Situation doesn't look good, sweetheart.
要请最顶尖的律师得花多少钱？
How much money would it cost to hire the best family lawver in the countrv?
很多钱，过来
Alot. Come here.
过来
Come here.
叛徒
Judas.
这笔钱应该够了
That should get you started.
十万美元
Hundred grand.
你没有任何损失
What do you got to lose?
他只想见你
He just wants to meet you.
只见一面
One time.
你不喜欢的话
You don't like the situation...
就走人
...walk away.
就这么简单？
And that's it?
没错，钱你可以留着
That's it. And you keep the money.
联邦调查局洛杉矶分局
他说什么？
What did he sav?
好吧
All right, look, look.
你的当事人在七个国家
Your client is wanted on 24 counts of electronic crimes...
因为24项电脑罪行遭到通缉
...in 7 different countries.
他持芬兰护照
He has a Finnish passport.
芬兰政府并不承认这些罪行
These allegations are  not recognized as crimes.
你们的法律对他无效
Your laws don't apply.
宜家小子，这儿没有芬兰国旗
Do you see a Finnish flag hanging on the wall, IK EA bov?
他说什么？
What did he sav?
他说宜家家具是瑞典公司
He said IK EA is Swedish.
他听得懂英文嘛
He understands English, huh?
让我跟他谈谈
Let me talk to him.
请便
He's all yours.
你完蛋了
You're fucked up now, Hamlet.
宜家家具都得自己组装
The thing is, they have you put the furniture together yourself.
他一再说他有保持缄默的权利
Mv client has reserved his right not to answer any questions.
全世界最顶尖的骇客
Whv would the best hacker in the world...
为何要冒坐牢的危险来美国？
...risk life imprisonment bv coming into the continental U.S.?
他刚才说什么？
Okay, what did he just sav?
他不想错过影集“我要活下去”
He never misses an episode of Survivor.
他真的那么说？
Did he really sav that?
你很好笑
You're funnv.
你体重多少？
How much do you weigh?
我的体重？
How much do I weigh?
我有需要再找你
We'll call you if we need you.
去死吧
Eat a dick.
别笑得那么高兴
Wipe that smile off your face.
一年前我曾指挥…
A vear ago, I was head of the largest
全球最大的电脑犯罪专案小组
cvber-criminal task force in the world.
但是我太累了
But I burned out.
我失去控制
I snapped.
向一名嫌犯的手开枪
I shot a suspect in the hand.
你知道只用一只手打电脑会有多么困难吗？
You know how difficult it is to work a Keyboard with one hand?
你不明白
You don't understand.
你再怎么狠都比不上他
Whatever you want to  do to me, he'll do worse.
我死定了
I'm already dead.
我只有回欧洲找朋友才有救
Mv only chance is back in Europe. I have friends there.
把你知道的告诉我
Tell me what I want to know.
我就让你坐头等舱飞回欧洲
You'll be on the first thing smoking. First class.
美国政府很大方
Courtesv of the U.S. Government.
他是谁？
Who is he?
我不知道名字
I don't know his name.
你不知道他的名字？
You work for him.You don't know?
不知道
你应该知道些什么吧
Tell me something.
我把知道的告诉你
I'll tell you what I know.
他存在一个你想像不到的世界
He exists in a world bevond your world.
你的幻想就是他的实现
What we only fantasize, he does.
他没有什么是得不到的
He lives a life where nothing is beyond him.
但是那全是一个假象
But you know what? It's all a feint.
他表面是个风度翩翩的大富翁
For all his charm and charisma, his wealth, his expensive toys...
骨子里却是冷酷无情的杀手
...he is a driven, unflinching, calculating machine.
他只要得到他想要的
He takes what he wants, when he wants...
就消失无踪
...and disappears.
我要怎么找到他？
So how do I find him?
你找不到他，只有他来找你
You don't find him. He finds you.
过程是这样的
Here's how it works.
他的手下接我去找他
His people pick me up. Take me to him.
然后他告诉我该做什么
He tells me what he wants me to do.
我当场完成任务
I do the job right there.
拿了钱就走
I get paid, and I leave.
故事很精采，但你什么也没说
That's a really nice story, but you haven't told me shit, have you?
抱歉，长官，你有电话
Excuse me, sir. You have a call.
帮我留言
Take a message.
是分局长乔伊
It's assistant director Joy.
他说很重要
He said it's important.
我只能说我替他做了什么
I can only tell you what I've done for him.
好吧，这总是个开始
Well, that's a start.
感谢你放了我的当事人
Thank you. You've just let my client go free.
你剥夺他的权利还动手打人…
You denied his right to counsel- -
对不起
Excuse me.
你去死吧
Yeah, and you eat the dick!
分局长乔伊找我，我是罗伯
Yes, I got a call from A.D. Joy. This is Roberts.
请稍等一下，长官
Hold for just one moment, sir.
我是乔伊
Joy.
我是罗伯，你找我
Yeah, Roberts. You needed me.
你没找我？
You didn't cal
没有，你想干嘛？
No, Roberts. What do you want?
你应该让我替你买套西装
You should 've let me buy you a suit, Stanley.
我穿这样就很好，谢谢
I'm happv with what I'm wearing.
你太邋遢了
Ignorance is bliss.
想我吗？
Miss me?
史丹利，这是盖布洛
Stanley, Gabriel
史丹利老弟，好帅的夹克
Big Stan. Nice suit.
谢了
Thanks.
人家说佛要金装、人要衣装
Thev sav the clothes make the man.
你相信这一套？
You buy it?
不信，来杯酒？
Hope not. Drink?
我大老远跑来不是为了喝酒
I flew 1500 miles for this meeting. How about we get to the point?
不对，事实上…
No. Actually,
你大老远跑来是为了十万元，但那不是重点
you flew 1500 miles for 100 grand. But that's not the point.
希嘉，这是史丹利
Helga. Meet Stanley.
－你好，史丹利 －希嘉
- Hello, Stanley. - Helga.
盖布洛，我没什么耐性
Look, I don't have a lot of patience, Gabriel
也许你能帮我个忙
Maybe you can help me with something.
过来看看
Take a look at this.
你觉得怎样？限制进入
你知道我不能碰电脑
You know I can't touch that.
你喝龙舌兰酒吗？
Do you like tequila, Stanley?
搞什么
This is bullshit.
你对我有要求，我对你也一样
You want something from me, and I from you.
国防资料库，128位元密码
DOD d-base, 128-bit encryption.
怎么样？不可能吗？
What do you think? Impossible?
没有不可能的事
Nothing's impossible.
很好，你一定能破解
Good. Maybe slide
你要利用电脑虫侵入系统
in a Trojan horse hiding a worm?
也许吧，这是面试吗？
Is this an interview?
算是吧，马可
Sort of. Marco.
给他一点犒赏
Give him some incentive.
你在干嘛？
Hey, what are you doing?
放轻松
Relax, Stanley.
我听说世上最顶尖的骇客
I have been told that the best crackers in the world...
60分钟内就能破解
...can do this in 60 minutes.
不幸我要你在60秒内破解
Unfortunately, I need someone to do it in 60 seconds.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding.
不是，开始
Afraid not. Go.
快起来
Get up, get up!
55秒
Fifty-five.
快动手吧
Get on with it.
这算什么？
What the hell is this?
别浪费时间
Time's a-wasting, big guy.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
45秒
Forty-five seconds.
拒绝进入
她很棒，对吧？
Oh, she's good, isn't she?
搞什么鬼？天啊
What's going on here? Jesus Christ.
拒绝进入
时间不够
More time, more time!
快点
Come on, Stan!
20秒…19秒…
Twenty. Nineteen.
15秒
Fifteen.
拒绝进入
快点
Come on.
10秒…9秒…
Ten. Nine.
拒绝进入
3秒…
Three.
2秒…
Two.
1秒…
One.
完了，你死了
Too bad. You gotta die.
不，等等
No, wait!
我只是耍你的
I was just fucking with you, Stan.
准许进入国防部资料库
就是他了
That's our guy.
离我远一点
Get away from me.
我真的很想帮你
I really want to help you, Stan.
你就是那样帮我吗？
Like you helped me in there?
－那只是个考验 －考验？
- That was a test, Stan. - A test.
你通过了
And you passed.
我太傻了，竟然会被你说服
I don't know why I let you talk me into this.
我以为你想救你女儿
You're saving your daughter.
我为了她什么都肯做
I'd do anything for her,
但是如果我死了一切都完了
but if I end up in a box or in jail... ...then I really can't help her.
我要拿了钱上法庭
I'm taking my money and going back to court!
你只有十万元
With your little $100,000?
你有钱，你前妻更有钱，动动脑筋吧
Melissa will throw $500,000 back at you. Think!
我被人拿枪指着叫我侵入…
I'm thinking that you'll put a gun to my head just to see if I can...
有人在，我尿不出来
I can't pee in front of an audience.
我再跟你说一遍
Let me break it down to you, Stanley, one last time.
你住在拖车屋
You live in a trailer.
你不但有前科，工作也没前途
You're a felon. You work a dead-end job.
你急着想把女儿要回来
And you desperately want your daughter back.
盖布洛是你唯一的机会
Gabriel is your only shot.
你要好好把握
Take it.
我担心咱们的新朋友
I'm concerned about our new friend.
别吃他的醋
Oh, now, don't be jealous.
他肯定不会好好完成任务
I don't see him dragging his sorrv arse over the finish line.
史丹利，我以为你跑了
Thought we lost you.
告诉我你要做什么
Tell me what the deal is.
我要在我家办一个小小的聚会
The deal is that we're having a little gathering at the house.
一起来，我就告诉你
Come and I'll explain it to you there.
各位
Gentlemen,
没有好消息就别说
if it's not good news, don't sav it.
你心中会燃起一丝希望的火花
Actually, we have a rav of hope in the darkness of your life.
我们到机场时这两个人也在
When we grabbed Torvalds at the airport, these two guys were there.
你看看
Check this out.
几个小时后他们又出现
Recognize those two same guys, a few hours later. And then...
你猜谁来了？
...guess who shows up.
史丹利贾森
Stanley Jobson.
电脑杂志96年年度风云人物
Wired magazine's 1996 Man of the Year.
当年他是骇客的精神领袖
A burnout now, but the hacker Zeitgeist then.
他是我逮到的
Yeah, I know Jobson, I arrested him.
你跑来洛杉矶干嘛？
Whv are you in L.A., Stan?
他前妻和女儿住在这儿
His ex-wife and daughter live in Malibu.
她继父是影片公司老板
The new husband owns Backdoor Films,
他专门拍色情片
a shady porn production house.
虽然是录影带，拍得还算不错
The production value's good, considering that they shoot on video.
有几部的女主角是他老婆
His wife is in some of the videos.
我知道，她是色情女星
I know. She's like an actress.
很好，说完了吗？
That's great. Are you done?
那女的是谁？
Who's the girl
我们还不知道
Actually, sir, we don't know vet.
她是个大美女
She's a serious piece of talent.
他一点也配不上她
Man, she's way out of his league.
查出她的身分
Find out who she is.
我要监视她前妻家
Sit on the ex-wife's house.
没问题
You got it.
史丹利，下来吧
Stanley, you want to get wet?
我没穿泳裤
I don't have a suit.
你不用穿
You don't need one.
来嘛
Come on, Stan.
待会吧
Later.
正点，喝一杯吧
Some view. Let's get a drink.
打开泳池灯光
Pool lights on.
你是怎么办到的？
So how did you do it?
－什么？ －破解密码
- Do what? - Break the code.
我从后门放进一个逻辑炸弹
I dropped a logic bomb through the trap door.
才怪，你没有时间
No, you didn't. You didn't have time.
你喝什么？
What'll you have?
威士忌
Scotch.
老实说吧，你一定有高招
You can do better than that.
我知道密码
I used a password sniffer.
你是怎么知道的？
How did you do it?
不晓得，我的脑海浮现密码
I don't know exactly. I see the code in my head.
我不会解释
I can't explain it.
我给你看一样东西
Let me show you something.
不错吧？
Pretty impressive, huh?
我要你放一只电脑虫
So, what we need from you is a worm.
超级电脑虫
A hydra, actually.
这种电脑虫能破解加密系统
A multiheaded worm to sniff out digital footprints across an encrvpted network.
什么样的加密系统？
What kind of cipher?
威能加密系统
A Vernam encryption.
它一旦启动，编码就自动销毁，它也是128位元加密系统
The Key code is destroved upon implementation. And it's a true 128-bit encryption.
其实是512位元
Well, actually, we're talking a 512-bit.
那就更不可能了
That's definitely not possible.
我给你一千万美元
What if I give you 10 million dollars?
这就能解决你的问题吧
That would cover all your problems. Yes?
你还是认为不可能？
Unless, of course, it's not possible.
你考虑看看
But you think about it.
它不会咬人的
It won't bite you. I promise.
这不只是多荧幕系统
This is not just a multi-screen system.
而且使用DS3超宽频连线
It has a DS-3 connection.
同时能进入七个不同的网路
We can access 7 different networks simultaneously.
你必须破解它的中央加密程式
It has a central encryption you have to crack...
才能进入它的系统，试试看
...to utilize the system.  Try it.
没被枪指着我还真不习惯
It'll be hard without a gun to my head.
也许我该拿枪指着你
Maybe I should put a gun to your head.
你不是盖布洛的女友吗？
I thought you were Gabriel's.
我跟你想像的不一样
I'm not what you think I am.
金姬
Ginger.
有头脑的女人也能让你兴奋
You surprised that a girl with an IO over 70 can give you a hard-on?
还是不可能吗？
So is it impossible?
没有不可能的事
Nothing's impossible.
很好，那就一言为定了
Good. So we have a deal
早安
Morning.
你该说午安吧
You mean afternoon?
我想借用你的车去一个地方
Can I borrow your car for something?
好啊
Sure.
－拿去 －谢谢你
- There you go. - Thank you.
如果你想去找荷莉
Hey, Stan, if you're going to see Holly...
你最好穿得体面一点
...I suggest you re-evaluate the way you look.
这只是个建议
Just a thought.
妈，快接电话
Come on, Mom, pick up.
荷莉，你妈又迟到了？
Mom late again?
她马上就来
She'll be here in a minute.
我要计程车行的电话号码
Hi. Can I have the phone number for Yellow Cab?
想搭车吗？
Need a lift?
爸
Daddy!
你怎么会在这儿？
Oh, what are you doing here?
我好想你
I missed you so much.
我也好想你，宝贝
Oh, I missed you too, baby.
我带了礼物
I brought you something.
天啊，好可爱哦
Oh, my gosh. It 's so cute.
被妈知道了，你就会被关进牢里
Oh, Dad. If Mom finds out, she'llhave you thrown in jail
没关系，你要回家吗？
It's okay, baby. You want a lift home?
当然了
Of course I do.
来吧
Come here.
好了
All right.
你好重
You are heavv.
好帅的车
Nice car.
谢了
Hey, thanks.
你妈的车吗？她在家？
Is that Mommy's car? Is she home?
那是继父的车
That's my stepdad's car.
听我说
So listen to me.
我有办法跟你团聚
I found a way for us to be together.
我不希望你出事
I don't want anything to happen to you.
不会有事的
Everything's going to be fine.
不会有问题的，相信我
Everything's going to be okay. Just trust me.
爸，我爱你
I love you, Daddy.
过来，我也爱你
I love you. Come here.
回家吧，再见
You go home. Okay? Bye.
－我好想你 －我也是，进去吧
- I miss you. - I miss you too. Go.
甜心
Oh, sweetheart.
这个
Hey.
过来
Come here.
好了，进去吧
It's okay. Go. Go.
快进去
Go.
你是什么人？
Who the hell are you?
一个朋友的朋友
A friend of a friend.
该死
Shit.
可恶
Oh, fuck. Fuck!
史丹利，站住
Hold it! Stanley!
去开车
Go!
可恶
Oh, fuck.
该死
Oh, fuck!
别动
Don't move!
别乱来
Don't move.
过来
Come here.
你看看
Look at this.
你为什么逃跑？
What were you running for?
你要逮捕我吗？
You arresting me?
因为你违反假释条例离开德州
For violating your parole bv leaving Texas without permission?
或是逃避联邦探员追捕
Or evading an officer
还差点害我没命？
and almost getting me killed in the process?!
不，我不会逮捕你
No, I'm not arresting you.
那么你想干嘛？
Then why are we talking?
你为什么来洛杉矶？
What are you doing in L.A.?
度假
Vacationing.
度假才怪
Vacationing, right.
法官准许你探望女儿吗？
The judge is allowing you to see your daughter?
去死吧
Fuck you.
你才去死吧
Fuck you? Oh?
你就是要嘴硬，是吧？
You just want to get right down to it?
好吧
Okay, fine.
我可以帮你要回女儿
I can help you with your daughter.
只要你肯帮我
You help me, I'll help you.
不好意思，事实上是…
You'llhave to forgive me. The fact that...
你把我关起来，我不太相信你
...you put me in jail doesn't inspire trust.
你侵入FBI的资料库
You put a virus in an FBI program
用病毒破坏整个系统
and set it back two years.
他们非法阅读国民的电子邮件
Thev were reading ISP subscribers' e-mail It was illegal
我只是伸张正义
I did what the judges wouldn't do!
你犯了法
You broke the law!
我们都尽了责任
We both did what we had to do.
但是那项计划还是照常进行
And your program is back in full swing.
我很想叙旧，但是你不逮我…
Nice trip down memorv lane, but if you aren't arresting me...
你就是不肯合作
Not getting a lot of cooperation here.
前几天我碰到你老友托沃
I ran into your friend Torvalds the other dav.
他也来度假
He was vacationing too.
两名顶尖骇客怎么都在洛城？
What are the odds of you being in L.A. At the same time?
我最爱迪士尼乐园
I'm just a sucker for Disnevland.
说完了吗？
We done?
很好
Good.
帮我跟托沃问好
Tell T orvalds I said hello.
他死了，你不小心也会没命
You can tellhim yourself if you're not careful He's dead.
给我一张名片
Give me a card.
想到什么就打给我
You think of anything to sav, call me.
抱歉打歪你鼻梁
Sorrv about your nose.
史丹利，你根本搞不清状况
You're in way over your head.
我知道
I know.
你要我监视他吗？
You want me to watch him?
好，去安排
Yeah, set it up.
今天我够倒霉了，现在更糟
I've had a shitty dav so far, but I think it just got worse.
你要开枪，还是要告诉我…
Either shoot me, or tell me...
你为何戴窃听器
...why you're wearing that wire.
办不到
Can't do that.
你到底是谁？
Who are you, Ginger?
我不能说
I can't tell you.
你是谁？
Who are you?
他知道了会杀死我
He'll kill me if he finds out.
那不是我的问题
That's not my problem, is it?
你不信任我怎么行？
You're asking for a lot of faith without giving me any.
你把我拖下水
You brought me into this mess.
我要知道你的身分
I deserve to know who's plaving me.
你是谁？
Who are you?
金姬
我是缉毒局干员
I'm DEA, Stanley.
老天爷
Holy shit.
我们要抓的是盖布洛
We're after Gabriel
把电脑虫给他，拿了钱就走吧
Give him the worm take the money  and get out of here. That's all
你们真是亲热
This looks friendly.
你知道我总是热情洋溢
You know me, I'm a friendly girl
来吧，史丹利，去喝杯咖啡
Come on, Stanley. Let's get coffee.
你听过剑鱼行动吗？
Ever heard of Operation Swordfish?
没有
No.
那么你一定会吓一跳
Then you'll appreciate the ironv.
浓缩意大利咖啡
Triple espresso.
－来两杯 －好
- Two. - Okay.
80年初缉毒局成立傀儡公司
In the '80s, the DEA set up a network of dummy corporations...
为了洗贩毒赃款及搜集证据
...as a front to launder drug money and gather evidence.
后来这些公司开始赚很多钱
But these companies started to make a lot of money.
1986年剑鱼行动结束时
In 1986, when it was terminated,
银行帐户共有四亿美元
$400 million was in these accounts.
这笔巨款消失无踪
Monev that just sort of disappeared.
它没消失，它一直在生利息
It didn't disappear. It sat, earning interest.
那是15年前的事
That's 15 years ago. You know
你知道现在有多少钱吗？
how much money that is todav?
95亿美元
Nine and a half billion.
这简直是暴利
This is a sweet deal
只要透过电话线通过防火墙
We go in over the phone lines,  pop the firewal...
丢进超级电脑虫
...drop in the hydra
就能轻松地偷走这笔巨款
and wait for the money.
你想得太容易了
Arert you getting ahead of yourself?
为了能进入伺服器
To access the cluster,
你要找有接驳网路主干线的银行
you need a bank on  the backbone of the network.
你知道有多难找吗？
You now how long that'll take to find?
没问题，往后看
Not a problem. Look behind you.
世界银行
干杯
Cheers.
他们看起来像社交名流
These fellows might wear Armani...
但是走起路来就知道是军人
...but they have the swagger of ex-militarv.
或是保镖，不过我看是佣兵
Maybe bodvguards, but they look like mercs to me.
这里面一定有鬼
Something's going on.
他们有两条DS3超宽频线路
Thev have two DS-3 trucks.  That's serious bandwidth.
感应器显示屋内散发强大热量
Thermal scopes show a huge heat load.
很可能是电脑主机
Could be mainframes.
房子登记在名人地产名下
The house was listed bv Celebrity Estates.
两星期前被一家公司承租
It was leased two weeks ago bv a blind corporation.
没有任何其它资料
No other info on them vet.
等一下
Wait a minute, Joe.
穿蓝色衬衫的家伙
Blue shirt, pinstripe.
就是他
Oh, veah, that's him.
他就是主谋
That's our man right there.
你正好来看史丹利找到电脑虫
Just in time to watch Stanley find our worm.
我念大学时写了一个密码程式
In college, I created the source code for the worm I use.
加州理工学院校友会
拒绝进入
那儿还有原始的资料处理器
In the basement is the only PDP-10 still active and on the Internet.
但是很少人知道
Not many people know it.
那架老旧的网路交易伺服器
It's an IT S machine,
还能上线作业
kept online for historical sake.
把电脑虫藏在那儿不会被发现
I hid my worm there, where no one would ever look.
使用者确认中
准许进入
找到了
Voil?
资料解码中
干得好
Good man.
亚力山卓，维吉尼亚州
参议员，出了状况
Senator, we have a problem.
参议员
Senator.
你惹上了大麻烦
Seems you're in a predicament.
是吗？我不懂
Is that right?I don't follow.
下载我寄的档案
Download your file.
参议员
Senator...
你知道是谁给我的吗？
You know where I got these?
联邦调查局副局长
From the deputy director of the FBI
他觉得我会有兴趣
He thought I might be interested.
请恕我直言
Sir, do you think...
你以为我无法掌控这项行动？
...there is any aspect of this  operation I am not aware of?
我要取消这项行动，放个假吧
We are aborting the operation. Take a vacation.
放假？我曾让你失望吗？
A vacation? Have I ever failed you, sir?
这不是重点
That's not really the point, is it?
这才是我的重点
It 's my point.
你忘了任务的目标
You're losing sight of our objective.
太危险了，我们要重新评估
The risks are too great.
用别的方法募集资金
We'll seek alternative means of finance.
这项行动继续进行
This operation is moving ahead.
一切都在我的掌控中
Everything is under control
小伙子
Son...
假如你养一只巨大的洛威拿犬
...let's just sav you've got a 200-pound Rottweiler.
它对你很忠心
Now, he loves you.
它的责任是保护你
It's his job to protect you.
但它咬你一口，你就得杀了它
But if he bites you, you got to put him down.
谁知道它会咬谁？你懂吗？
Can never tell who he might bite next. You understand?
我懂，参议员
Yes, I do understand, senator.
西岸的麦克锡堡有一组人马
I think we got a team on the West Coast. Fort MacArthur.
派他们去找盖布洛
Maybe they should pay our friend a visit.
快点
Come on.
网路协定确认中
Network IP range. Confirmed.
一定要确认，确认
Please confirm. Confirm. Confirm.
成功了
We are cruising!
太好了
Oh, veah.
下一个
Next. And next.
太简单了
Too easy.
不，别断线
No, don't. No, no, no. Yes!
百分之三
Three percent, please.
完了，我完了
Oh, fuck. I'm fucked.
不…可恶
No, no, no. Fuck you!
该死，不会吧？
Shit, there's no fucking way.
我退步了
I'm rusty. Rusty.
好了，我要把你变成…
Okay. Time to disguise you...
内部的伪装档
...as an internal destruction.
快点…谢谢
Quick, quick. Thank you.
回复
Return.
3、2、1，快点
Three, two, one, go. Come on.
快好了
Close.
组合加密演算程式
宝贝
Oh, baby.
好耶
组合传输编译程序
电脑虫完成
你得改写密码
Now I've just got to modifv the code.
银行的IDS不能登录…
The bank's IDS logs everv packer...
22或80传输控制协定
...that go to any port other than the 22 or 80 TCP.
天啊
Holy shit.
爱德居酒庄1996年份白酒
White, white.
不是
Nope.
快点…快点…
Come on, come on.
找到了
Here we go.
1926、1996…
Twenty-six. Ninety-six. Nine...
可恶
Oh, shit!
怎么了？你好像见鬼了
What's the matter? You look like you've seen a ghost.
我们得谈谈
We gotta talk.
－那就开车兜兜风 －何不在这儿谈？
- Let's take a drive. - Can't we talk here?
不行
We shouldn't.
你听过胡迪尼吗？
Ever heard of Harrv Houdini?
他不像现在的魔术师只会做秀
He wasrt like todav's magicians, only interested in television ratings.
他是艺术家
He was an artist.
他能在人群中让大象凭空消失
He could make an elephant disappear in a full theater.
他用什么方法？
You know how he did that?
障眼法
Misdirection.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
障眼法
Misdirection.
只要亲眼目睹就会信以为真
What the eves see and the ears hear, the mind believes.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
有人跟踪，坐好了
We've got a tail,Hold on.
该死
Shit.
天啊
Jesus. Jesus!
我得想办法，你来开车
Take the wheel
什么？
What?
你来开车
Take the wheel
可恶
Holy shit!
他们是谁？
Who are those guys?
天啊
Jesus!
你在干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
天啊
Jesus!
快开车
Drive, Stan.
快点
Move!
我不会开这辆车
I can't drive this thing.
快学呀
Learn!
快走
Move it.
快点！
Come on!
左转，左转
Hard left! Hard left!
继续开
Keep going!
冲过去
Go!
上车
Get in the car.
你先告诉我这是怎么回事
Not until you tell me what I'm involved in.
史丹利，我喜欢你
Look, Stanley, I like you.
也把你当朋友
You're on my good side.
但是别以为我会心软
But don't confuse  kindness with weakness.
你只剩12小时，快上车吧
You have 12 hours to get the hydra. So get in the car.
史丹利，你还好吧？
Stanley, are you okay?
我眼睁睁看那疯子大开杀戒
I just saw that maniac  murder people in the street.
我好得不得了
I'm fucking great.
你不能走，不会有事的
You can't leave. It 'll all work out.
相信我
You gotta trust me.
鬼才相信你
Trust you? Yeah.
你是缉毒局，联邦探员在盯我
You're DEA, I got the feds up my ass...
我也搞不清状况
...and I don't know what's going on here.
查不出他的老板就前功尽弃
If we don't find out who he works for, we'llhave to start over.
这不是我的问题，我才不在乎
That's not my problem. I don't care who he works for.
荷莉呢？你不在乎她吗？
What about Holly? Do you give a shit about her?
你只要完成任务就能要回女儿
Finish the job. We'll get your daughter back.
我保证
I promise.
班德，奥勒冈州
美好的原野风光
Ah, the great American outdoors.
我不晓得溪钓有什么好玩
Yet I never understood the appeal of fly -fishing.
泡在水里大半天却钓不到鱼
A bit too much like masturbation for me without the payoff.
这不是保育区吗？
This is a catch-and-release stream, isn't it?
对，应该是吧
Yeah, I believe it is.
这也未免太讽刺了，参议员
You must see the ironv in that, senator.
你身为打击犯罪委员会主席
Chairman of the subcommittee on crime...
却在保育区钓鱼
...fishing in a catch-and-release stream.
我尽心尽力，你怎能背叛我？
How could you do it to me, Jim? After all we suffered.
我换了太多身分都忘了我是谁
I've changed my identity so often I don't know who I am anymore.
就快成功了，你怎么能出卖我？
How could you do it? We were so close to our goal
FBI盯上你
The FBI was watching you.
你想杀死我
You tried to kill me.
你背叛了理想
You've misplaced your loyalty, senator.
也出卖了美国
You've sold out America.
伟大的爱国情操永远不死
Patriotism does not have a four-vear shelf life.
很可惜政客会死
But politicians do.
你想干什么？
What are you doing with that?
第三任总统杰佛逊
Thomas Jefferson
曾经射杀一名叛国贼
once shot a man for treason.
慢着，第三任总统…
Hold the phone. Thomas Jeff...
史丹利，你好吗？
Stan. How are you?
－很好 －完成了吗？
- Fine. - Finished?
你是史丹利贾森吗？
Is this Stanley Jobson,
身分证号码
social security number 669547311?
是的
这里是瑞士银行
I'm calling from Credit Suisse to notify you...
你的新户头刚汇入一千万美元
...that $ 10 million was transferred into your new account.
我答应你的
As promised.
谢了
Thanks.
没我的事了吧
So I'm done, then.
就快了，跟我来
Soon. Walk with me.
我要违背我的原则
Against my better judgment,
跟你说我是谁
I'm going to tell you who I am.
不用，我知道了
I know who you are.
是吗？
Do you?
你以为我是抢匪，但是…
I think you think I'm a bank robber.
其实我跟你一样
But the truth is, I'm just like you.
你跟我不一样，你是杀人魔
Like me? No. Because you're a murderer.
我是杀了人，但我有道德观念
That I am, and worse. But I do have ethics.
我也有原则
Rules I adhere to.
你为什么跟我说这些？
Whv are you telling me this?
你听完了就会懂
Well, if you listen, then you'll know.
你问我那些人是谁，我来告诉你
You asked who those men were. I'll tell you.
胡佛在50年代成立秘密组织
Hoover started a secret organization in the '50s,
名为“黑牢”
called Black Cel
宗旨是捍卫国家的自由
To protect our freedoms.
我不在乎，我只在乎我女儿
I don't care. All I care about is my daughter.
我说的就是你女儿
I'm talking about your daughter.
我说的是你、你女儿
You, your daughter...
以及两亿名自由的美国公民
...and 200 million Americans who take their freedoms for granted.
我了解了
I see.
你不了解捍卫自由的代价
You don't know what it takes to protect our freedoms. That's my job.
我的责任就是保护你的生活
To protect your way of life.
你跟你的狐群狗党
So you're really stealing all this money
是为了小老百姓才偷那笔钱的吗？
just to protect little old me.
没错史丹利，因为打仗需要钱
That's right, Stanley. Because wars cost money.
打仗？
War?
我们跟谁打仗？
Who are we at war with?
危害美国的每一个人
Anvone who impinges on America's freedom.
也就是恐怖份子
Terrorist states, Stanley.
我们必须以牙还牙
Someone must bring their war to them.
他们炸一座教堂，我们就炸十座
Thev bomb a church, we bomb 10.
他们劫机，我们就炸掉机场
Thev hijack a plane, we take out an airport.
他们处决美国游客
Thev execute American tourists,
我们就炸毁一座城市
we nuke an entire city.
我们要以暴制暴
We make terrorism so horrific...
这样他们才不敢攻击美国人
...that it's unthinkable  to attack Americans.
你不是透过网路偷钱
You're not using the phone lines.
你是抢银行
You're going into the bank.
你也要一起去
And you're coming with us.
24小时后就结束
It'll all be over in 24 hours.
你发财了，史丹利
You're a rich man, Stanley.
你很快就能跟女儿逍遥过一生
Soon you'll be on a vacht with your daughter, eating bonbons.
实现美国梦
The American dream.
你想想看
And just think:
你这算是对美国有小小的贡献
You'llhave done your small part in ensuring America's way of life.
你是个英雄
You're a hero, Stan.
没关系，让他走
Don't worry. Let him go.
他一定会回来
He'll be back.
好了，准备好，出发吧
Okay, load them up. Let's move out.
走吧
Let's go!
退后
Back!
天啊
快点…快点…
Move it, move it! Let's move!
照我的话，手放在头上
Let's go. Hands behind your head. Let's go!
钥匙给我
Key, please.
钥匙？我不知道你在说什么
What Key? I don't know about any Key.
钥匙
Key.
走吧
Let's move!
进去
Back of the bank. Now!
快走吧，快点
Let's go, let's go!
蹲下，所有人蹲下来
Down. Everyone down!
等我一下
Just wait here.
梅莉莎？
Melissa?
荷莉
Holly!
天啊
Oh, God.
荷莉
Holly!
宝贝
Baby!
宝贝，宝贝
Baby. Baby.
可恶，荷莉
Shit!
联邦探员罗伯 不，放开人质
No! Release the hostage!
救救我
Help me!
不，放开她，放开她
Let her go! Let her go!
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事
I'm good.
这是你的错
That was your decision!
不，是你的错
No, you did that!
你还要害死多少人？
How many people die is up to you!
25分钟后把飞机开到机场
I want that plane on the runway in 25 minutes!
他要在25分钟后上飞机
He wants a plane on the runway in 25 minutes.
我建议你乖乖照办
Mv suggestion, sir? You give it to him!
他要飞机，我就给他飞机
He wants a plane? I'll give him a goddamn plane.
史丹利，把事情做完
Finish the job.
我要先见到女儿
Not until I see my daughter!
你要见她？带上来
You want to see her? Get him his daughter!
爸
Dad!
天啊，宝贝，你没事吧？
Oh, Jesus. Baby, are you okay?
没事了
It's okay, it's okay.
你这坏蛋
You son of a bitch.
你以为我想这么做吗？
You think I wanted it to come to this?
我愿意牺牲人命捍卫国家
I'll sacrifice any lives I have to to protect this countrv.
包括我自己的命
Including my own.
放了她
Let her go.
我就把钱偷给你
And I'll get your money.
你只要完成任务就能走
You finish the job, and you both go.
快点吧，史丹利
Come on, Stanley.
－我要光碟片 －光碟
- I need the disc. - Disc.
转帐中
你要转到哪个帐户？
How do you want it allocated?
平均分配到每个帐户
Spread evenly over the accounts.
总额95亿美元
好了，把女儿交给我
Come on. Done. Give me my daughter.
确认
Verify this.
没问题
Good.
把她带来
Get her.
你还好吗？没事了，走吧
You okay? Okay, come on.
史丹利，等等
Stanley, hold up.
干得好
Good job.
回头见
See you around.
不会了
I doubt it.
怎么回事？怎么回事？
What's happening? What's happening?
钱不见了
The money's gone.
－拦住她 －快跑
- Stop her! - Go! Run!
抓住她
快走
Go!
她出来了
She's coming out.
过来，过来
Come here, come here!
怎么回事？
What happened, Stan?
爆炸破坏了电脑时钟
The explosion scrambled the internal clock.
才不是，你耍了我
No, it didn't. You fucked me.
你杀了我就拿不到钱
You kill me, you'll never get a dollar.
这笔钱每分钟会换一个帐户
The money jumps everv 60 seconds from one account to another.
接下来十年都是这样
It'll do so for the next 10 years.
本来不会发生，现在没办法了
It wasrt supposed to happen for another six hours, but hev.
快想办法
Fix it.
我束手无策了
Unfortunately, I can't.
帐户有1024位元加密系统
The accounts are encrvpted with a 1024-bit cipher.
连我也通不过它的防火墙
Even I can't get through the firewal
我跟你谈个条件
So here's the deal
放走人质我就告诉你怎么取款
Let the hostages go and I'll tell you how to get the money.
皆大欢喜，没人受伤
We all walk away. Nobodygets hurt.
怎么样？
Deal
我正在考虑
I'm thinking.
不行，把金姬带来
No deal Get Ginger.
让开
Move out.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
把她吊起来
String her up.
不，住手
No. Don't do this.
不，等等…
No! Wait, Wait!
不，等等
Wait, Wait!
别乱动，这会很痛快的
Hey, stav stil lt'll feel real good.
不，别这么做
No, don't do this!
等等
不知道她能活多久？
How long will she live? 60 seconds?
你疯了
You're insane!
最多60秒
－55秒 －好吧
- Fifty-five. - Okay, okay.
你最好在系统中留了后门
- Hope you built in a back door. - Come on, come on.
快点，快点
Come on, come on.
30秒
Thirty.
半小时后飞机会到机场
Plane's on the runway in a half -hour.
很好
Good.
20秒
Twenty.
她快死了
She's dving.
给我闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
10、9、8…
Ten. Nine. Eight.
我要帐号
Accounts, accounts.
转帐中
好了
That's it.
3…
Three. Two.
转帐完成
好了，放她下来
There it is. Get her down!
－检查 －确认
- Check. - Verified.
把她放下来
Bring her down.
她是缉毒干员
She was DEA, Stan.
把人质带走
Move them out!
走吧，动作快点
Let's move. Quickly and quietly.
快走吧，所有的人快点
Move it. Come on, people.
走吧，走吧
Move. Move.
谁也不想让悲剧重演
No one wants a repeat of this morning.
方圆五哩的领空要净空
Keep your distance. Clear the air space for five miles.
他们要走了
Thev're on the move.
快点
Move, move.
看什么？
What?
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
你在想…
You're thinking:
不知道这个坏蛋
If that launcher was a suppositorv...
会把那支火箭筒拿来干嘛？
...would that bad man stick it up my ass?
你敢再瞪我一眼
Well, you eveball me once more, bov...
我就把这支火箭筒塞进你屁眼
...I'll stick it so far up your ass... ...you'll be begging me for this bullet.
各位，你们要留在巴士上
This bus is your new holding area.
如果你们乖乖合作
If you don't test your collars,
事情很快就会结束
this will all be over soon.
快去逮这可恶家伙吧
Let's get this son of a bitch.
你怎么能心安理得？
How can you justifv all this?
你没有为大局着想
You're not looking at the big picture.
我问你
Here's a scenario:
要是你能治好所有的疾病
You can cure all diseases,
但是你得杀死一名无辜孩童
but the price is that  you must kill one innocent child.
你肯下手吗？
Could you do it?
不肯
No.
你让我失望，我是在作好事
You disappoint me. It's the greatest good.
如果需要杀十名孩童呢？
How about 10 innocents?
这就对了，就算杀一千个人
Now you get it. How about 100? 1000?
也是为了保护我们的生活
To preserve our way of life.
你只要滥杀无辜就是恐怖份子
No man has the right to make that decision.You're just a terrorist.
你错了，史丹利
You're wrong, Stanley.
每天都有人白白送命
Thousands die everv dav for no reason.
你怎么不可怜他们？
Where's your bleeding heart for them?
难道捐钱给慈善机构就够了吗？
You give $20 to Greenpeace thinking you change the world.
我会让恐怖份子吓得不敢造次
What countrv willharbor terrorists when they see the consequences?
我可以花四千万元买一枚核弹
Did you know I can buy nuclear warheads in Minsk for 40 million?
买半打甚至还有折扣
Hell, I buy half a dozen, I even get a discount.
我们离机场还有20分钟车程
Advise Joy 20 minutes ETA at the airport.
控制中心，转告分局长
Control, please let A.D. Joy know we're 20 minutes from the airport.
我们20分钟后就到机场
好了吗？
Ready?
油加满了，可以起飞了
Bird's fueled, ready to go.
机长呢？
What about your pilot?
他来了
He's in the works now.
很好，上吧
All right. Let's do it.
这儿留一组人
Okay, I need a team over here.
其他人到外面
The rest of you, let's go outside.
该死
Fuck!
天啊，他在搞什么鬼？
Jesus. What the fuck is he thinking?
我以为你要去机场
Arert we going to the airport?
这只是障眼法
Misdirection, Stan.
你干嘛？你要去哪儿？
What are you doing? Where are you taking the thing?
看过“横冲直撞大逃亡”吗？
You see Sugarland Express?
你们在干嘛？
我不喜欢它的结局
Didrt like the way it ended.
快停下来
Pull over before you get...
他们该不会想飞天遁地吧
Thev can't be serious.
坐好了
Hold on!
请注意，进行空中追捕
Attention control, this has now become an aerial pursuit.
跑道上都是我的手下
I've also got people across the tarmac.
长官，我刚收到讯息
Sir, I've just been informed
巴士没有开往机场
that the bus is no  longer en route to LAX.
怎么回事？
What happened?
它冲破车队转到一街了
It broke through the vehicles and turned onto First Street.
那就赶到一街
All right. Let's go.
长官，巴士不在一街上
Sir, the bus is no longer on First Street.
那它在哪里？
Then where is it?
在空中
Airborne.
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
风速太强，他怕会撞到大楼
We have a strong wind condition.
叫他爬升
Tellhim to climb!
快爬升，快点
Climb, goddamn it! Climb!
大家趴下来
Down! Everybodydown!
一定要添加刺激的动作
Add action or excitement,
要不然就得改变宣传策略
or change the direction  of the entire campaign.
也许应该重新考虑
Maybe we ought to rethink the visual
我的天啊
Holy shit.
把大楼团团包围
Secure a perimeter around the building.
蔬散大厅每一个人
I want evervbodyout of this lobbv right now.
守住电梯和楼梯
Secure the elevators and stairs!
拘捕出来的每个人
Anybody coming out, detain them!
怎么回事？
What's going on?
哪些电梯到屋顶？
The elevators to the roof?
那里
Up there.
货运电梯呢？
And the freight elevator?
在后面
Rear of the building.
那里
That way.
史丹利老弟
Stan-man.
好好照顾荷莉，后会有期
Take care of your girl Maybe I'll see you around.
你逃不了的
No! It 's not going to end like this.
实际一点，史丹利
Come on, Stan.
你不能如愿以偿了
Not evervthing ends as you think it should.
况且，观众都爱看快乐结局
Besides, audiences love happv endings.
别乱动
Stay here!
该死，快点
Shit! Come on.
快走开
Move, move!
不，史丹利
No, Stanley!
快点
Come on.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
把武器拿走
Secure that weapon.
走吧
Let's go.
两位
Gentlemen.
你们是来认尸吗？
You here to identifv the bodv?
这具尸体的齿模显示他是…
The dentals match those the Israeli government sent us...
前以色列情报员盖布洛史尔
...for an ex-Mossad agent named Gabriel Shear.
对不起，长官
Excuse me, sir.
缉毒局没有金姬诺亚的记录
The DEA has no record of any Ginger K nowles working for them.
医院和殡仪馆也没有她的尸体
I checked all the hospitals and morgues, and I can't find her bodv.
继续查，尸体不会凭空消失
Look again. Bodies just don't disappear.
是的
Right.
他能让大象在人群中凭空消失
He could make an elephant  disappear in a full theater.
他用什么方法？
You know how he did that?
障眼法
Misdirection.
我是缉毒局干员
I'm DEA, Stanley.
把电脑虫给他，拿了钱就走
Give him the worm, take the money and get out of here.
只要亲眼目睹就会信以为真
What the eyes see and the ears hear, the mind believes.
障眼法
Misdirection, Stan.
他是大坏蛋，史丹利
This is a bad guy.
没有人会想念这个大坏蛋
Nobody's going to miss him.
你还好吧？
You all right?
我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
你先走，去看你女儿吧
Whv don't you get out of here? Go see your daughter.
好，谢了
Yeah, thanks.
再联络
We'll be in touch.
你这狡猾的家伙
You son of a bitch.
谢谢你，吃饱了吗？
Thank you. You're done?
吃饱了
Yes, I'm full.
那就走吧
Good. Let's go.
领航者，接下来去哪儿？
So, navigator, where's our next stop?
荷布克
Holbrook.
那儿有什么？
So what's in Holbrook?
森林乐园，爸
The Petrified Forest, Dad.
森林乐园
你要走40号州际公路
I think you take the l-40 to the 180.
没问题
Cool
好了
All right.
爸，你还好吧？
Are you okay, Dad?
我很好，亲爱的
Yeah, I'm fine, sweetheart.
放心啦，爸
Don't worry, Dad.
我们一切都会很好的
It's going to be okay. We're going to be fine.
我知道，亲爱的
I know, honey.
蒙地卡罗
我想从老板的帐户转帐出去
I'd like to transfer money from my employer's account.
帐号和密码
Mav I have your account number and password, please?
356127-G 356127G.
密码：剑鱼
Password: Swordfish.
你想转多少钱？
How much would you like to transfer?
全部，平均分配到这些帐户
All of it. Evenly over these accounts.
都办好了
It's done.
声名狼籍的恐怖份子艾拉哈萨
In international news, terrorist Allal bin-Hazzad...
据说今天遇害
...was killed today
他在地中海的游艇无故爆炸
in an unexplained explosion on a yacht in the Mediterranean.
哈萨遭到各国政府通缉
The elusive bin-Hazzad was thought responsible for...
他涉嫌犯下美国大使馆爆炸案
...the U.S. Embassy bombing in Istanbul earlier this month.
这是近来第三名恐怖份子伏法
This is the third killing of a terrorist leader in as many weeks.
导演：唐明尼克森纳
编剧：史基普伍兹
制片：乔尔·史尔芬 强纳森·卡任
约翰·屈伏塔
休杰·克曼
哈利·贝瑞